조이랑 결혼하겠다고 했어?
You said you'd marry Joey?
난 지칠대로 지친대다
감정이 고조된 상태였어
Okay, you have to realize,
I was exhausted, I was emotional.
누구 청혼이라도
받아들였을 거야!
I would have said yes to anybody.
우리 결혼했을 때처럼 말야!
Like that time
when you and I got married.
별 도움 안되는 얘기지?
I'm not helping.
우리 아기를 낳았으면서
조이 청혼을 승락했다구?!
So you said yes to him,
and you just had our baby?
그래, 그리고 원래 애아빠가
산모한테 선물 주는 법인데
That is right. And traditionally,
the daddy gives the mommy a present.
안줘도 난 봐줄거야!
But I am prepared to let that go.
우리 관계 다시 시작하고 싶은지
물어보려고 왔더니..
So when I came here to see if you
wanted to maybe start things up again..
내 제일 친한 친구랑
결혼약속을 해?!
you were engaged to my best friend?
어..
Well..
정말이야?
Really?
난 챈들러랑 제일
친한줄 알았는데?
I thought Chandler
was your best friend.
챈들러는 제일 오래된 친구고
조이가.. 말 돌리지마!
Well, Chandler's my oldest friend.
Joey's my.. No!
나 그만 가볼께
인사하려고 들어왔어
Hey, I'm gonna take off.
I just wanted to say goodbye.
레이첼이 너랑 결혼하겠다고
했다며?!
Rachel said she'd marry you?
이방이 아니네!
미안해요!
This isn't the right room. Sorry, folks.
프렌즈 시즌 9
'울지마, 아가'
'아들이에요!'
좋게 말해서, 네가 사온
장식물 대부분은 마음에 든다
I don't want to be negative. So I'll say
most of the signs you bought are good.
"딸이에요!"가 다 떨어졌대
내가 고쳐 놓을게
No, they ran out of "It's a Girl!"
But I can fix this one.
'아들이 "아니"예요!'
됐지?
See? Huh?
섹시하기도 하지
So sexy.
- 챈들러?
- 응?
- Honey?
- Yeah?
- 가서 눕지 그래?
- 괜찮아
- Honey, why don't you lie down?
- It's okay.
로스랑 레이첼 곧 올거잖아
회사도 가야해
Ross and Rachel will be back soon,
and then I gotta go to the office.
내몸에서 풍선이 나오나?
Am I producing them?
- 왜 그렇게 조는거야?
- 어젯밤에 못잤어
- Why are you so tired?
- I couldn't sleep last night.
오후에 있을 중요한 회의가
너무 걱정돼서 말야
I started worrying about this big
divisional meeting I have today.
걱정하면 할수록
잠이 더 안오더라고
The more I worried,
the more I couldn't sleep.
그러다가 이렇게 됐지
'지금자면 여섯 시간은 잘텐데'
You know, and then I was, like, "If I fall
asleep now, I'll get six hours' sleep.
'지금자면 다섯 시간은 잘텐데'
But if I fall asleep now,
I'll get five hours' sleep."
어쨌거나 잠을 못잤어
No matter what I did,
I couldn't fall asleep.
지금 그 얘기 들려줬더라면
너 금방 잠들었을텐데
You know what you should've done?
Told yourself that little story.
- 우리 왔어!
- 와!
- Hi.
- Hey.
- 어서와!
- 안녕
- Welcome home.
- Hi.
장식물은 피비가 산거야!
Phoebe did the signs.
다들 정말 고마워!
You guys, thanks for doing this.
사람들이 보내온
축하 선물좀 봐!
Look at all that stuff people sent.
어머나! 이건 아기엄마한테
꼭 필요한 거네!
Oh, my gosh. Look, there's something
every mother needs.
집안 가득 차는 어마어마한
고릴라 인형이라..
A giant, stuffed gorilla that takes up
the entire apartment.
도대체 누가 이런걸.. 어머
너희들이구나! 정말 마음에 든다!
What are people think..?
You guys, I love it.
로스는 어딨어?
Hey, so where's Ross?
택시에서 나머지 짐
내리고 있어
He's downstairs getting the stuff
out of the cab.
- 아직도 우리한테 화나있니?
- 너한테 더 화가 나있지
- Is he still mad at us?
- Well, you more than me.
나한텐 화 못내
애 낳아줬으니까
But he can't stay too mad at me.
I mean, I just had his baby.
그럼 어떡해!
난 애 못낳는데!
That's not fair. I can't do that.
로스가 너 여기 있는거 보면
안좋을것 같아
I'm not sure you should be here
when he comes up.
그럴줄 알았어!
나도 안오려고 했다구
I didn't think I should be here either.
But somebody said he'd be over it.
그런데 누가 지금쯤이면
로스 화가 풀렸을 거랬어!
내가 뭘 알겠냐? 더 큰 고릴라
사자고 한 사람인데
Hey, what do I know?
I wanted to get a bigger gorilla.
시카고, 뉴욕, 런던 쪽은
안정적입니다
The numbers we're seeing in Chicago,
New York and London are solid.
그러나 다른 많은 지사의
실적이 아주 저조해요
But many of our field offices
have reported disappointing yields.
보스턴, 애틀랜타, 휴스턴..
Boston is down. Atlanta is down.
Houston is down.
그밖에도 셀수없이 많지만
지루하게 열거하는 대신..
I could go on and on.
But instead of boring you..
내 계획을 설명하겠습니다
I'll go straight to my 42-point plan.
안녕하세요?
Walter.
정말 귀엽다!
She's just so cute.
저 귀 콱 물어뜯어서
사탕처럼 빨아먹고 싶어!
I just want to bite her ear off
and use it as a sucking candy.
피비!
Phoebe.
난 저 작은 발 떼어다가
빵속에 넣고 싶어!
But I could take one of those little feet
and put it in a pita pocket.
- 짐 다 정리했어
- 고마워, 노리개 젖꼭지는?
- Okay. I put most of the stuff away.
- Oh, great. The pacifiers?
- 벽장에
- 턱받이는?
- It's in the cupboard.
- The burping cloths?
- 옷장에
- 기저귀는?
- Linen closet.
- The diapers?
병원에
In the hospital.
- 너희집에 병원도 있니? 굉장하다!
- 기저귀를 병원에 두고 왔네
- Wow, you guys got a hospital? Fancy.
- No, I left the diapers at the hospital.
가방에 몇개 있지만
나가서 더 사올께
There's some in the bag,
but I'll run out and get some more.
그래, 고마워
All right, thanks.
카페에 들러서 머핀도 사다줄래?
Could you stop at the coffeehouse
and get me a muffin?
- 좋아, 어떤거?
- 글쎄, 생각해 볼께
- Sure. What kind?
- Let me think.
뭐가 좋을까?
What do I want?
천천히 잘 생각해봐
아주 중요한 문제니까..
Please, take your time.
It's an important decision, not like..
결혼 결정하곤 다르지
머핀 고르는 거잖아!
say, I don't know, deciding to marry
someone. This is about a muffin.
- 블루베리
- 블루베리 사다줄께
- Blueberry.
- Blueberry it is.
고마워
Thank you.
화난거 정말 오래도 간다
Wow, he's not letting this go, is he?
누가 아니래?
얼마나 저럴것 같니?
God, how long do you think
that's gonna last?
"우린 그때 헤어졌었어!" 사건은
그래도 빨리 끝났는데
I don't know. He got over the
"We were on a break" thing quickly.
몰라, 지금 당장은
걱정 안할거야
You know what,
I can't worry about it right now.
이렇게 예쁜 아기가 있잖아!
Because I've got the cutie little baby.
내가 이 앨 얼마나 사랑하는지 모를거야!
사랑스러워 어쩔줄 모르겠어!
I can't believe how much I love her.
I mean, I can't get enough of her.
지금 이순간도
난 얘가 미치게 그리워!
Like, right now? I miss her.
I actually miss her.
여기 있잖아, 봐
You know, that's her?
알아, 그치만 자고 있잖아
I know. I know, but she's sleeping.
깨어있을 때처럼 손발을 뻗고
비틀거리는걸 못보잖아
It's not like when she's awake
and I can see her stretch and wiggle.
참, 하품하는거 봤니?
Oh, my God, have you seen her yawn?
- 너무 귀엽더라
- 내말이
- It's so cute.
- I know.
언제 일어날것 같니?
When do you think
she's gonna wake up?
11시전에 안일어나면
나보러 깨워달라고 했어
She told me to ring her
if she's not up by 11.
면접을 봐야한대
She has a job interview.
하품하는건 그렇게 대단하고?
Okay, but the clouds part
when she yawns.
자는것좀 봐!
너무 예쁘다
God, look at her sleeping.
I love her so much.
- 깨워야겠어
- 안돼!
- I think I'm gonna wake her up.
- Rach, no.
자는 아기는
절대 깨우는게 아냐
You know, you're never
supposed to wake a sleeping baby.
내맘이야!
내가 낳았는걸?
Well, I can do whatever I want.
I made her.
이리온, 우리 아기!
착하지? 까꿍?
Come on, little girl.
Yes. Hello, Emma. Hello. Hi.
엠마가 내 대신
"내가 뭐랬어?"라고 하는구나
Well, I would say I told you so,
but she's kind of doing that for me.
그래, 엄마가 잘못했어
I'm sorry. Mommy's so sorry.
Go back to sleep.
다시 자, 착하지?
- 가슴 아프지?
- 정말 그래
- It breaks your heart, doesn't it?
- It really does.
우리 여기 얼마나
더 있어야 할까?
How long do you think
we have to stay?
다들 찬성하면 밀고 나가죠
Okay, if everyone's onboard,
it's settled.
챈들러?
Chandler?
- 챈들러?
- 네?
- Chandler?
- Yeah.
찬성인가요?
Are you onboard?
네
Yes.
그럼 챈들러가 털사지점을
맡아서 운영하도록 하세요
Well, then problem solved.
Chandler will run our office in Tulsa.
오클라호마가 마음에 들겁니다
You're gonna love Oklahoma.
우유도 주고, 기저귀도 갈고
트림도 시키고, 다 해봤어
All right. We already tried feeding her,
changing her, burping her..
이거 해볼래?
"과거로 돌아가 피비 말을 듣는다!"
Try this one. "Go back in time
and listen to Phoebe."
- 이거 한번 해보자
- 뭔데
- All right, here's something.
- What?
아기를 바짝 끌어안고
It says to try holding the baby
close to your body..
양 옆으로 빠르게 흔든다
and then swing her rapidly
from side to side.
좋아, 해볼께
Okay.
효과가 있는데?
It worked!
아냐, 토하느라고
잠깐 멈춘거야
No. Just stopped to throw up
a little bit.
어쩜 좋아?
Mon, what am I gonna do?
이거 몇시간째
울음을 안멈추잖아
It's been hours,
and it won't stop crying.
- "이거"가 아니라 아기야
- 글쎄, 잘 모르겠다
- She, Rach. Not it. She.
- Yeah. I'm not so sure.
- 아, 돌아버리겠다!
- 누가 아니래!
- Oh, my God, I'm losing my mind.
- Yeah, no kidding.
이게 바로 로스랑 잠자서
결코 좋을게 없다는 증거야!
All right, this just proves no good
can come from having sex with Ross!
안녕?
블루베리 머핀좀 싸줄래요?
Hey, Gunther. Can I get a couple
of blueberry muffins to go?
- 기저귀네?
- 맞아요
- Diapers, huh?
- Yep.
레이첼이 아기
낳았나보군
So I guess Rachel had your baby?
- 그래, 믿어져요?
- 아니?
- Yep. Can you believe it?
- Nope.
너랑 잠잤다는 것부터가
안믿어지는 걸
I can't even believe
she slept with you in the first place.
뭐?
그러니까 그말은..
You mean, like..
뭐라구요?
로스
Hey.
화난건 알지만
우리 얘기좀 하자
I know you're pissed at me,
but we have to talk about this.
난 할 얘기없어
Actually, we don't.
좋아, 엄밀히 말해서
난 잘못한거 하나도 없다
Fine. Okay. But I gotta say, technically,
I didn't even do anything wrong.
뭐?
잘못한게 없다구?
What? You didn't do anything wrong?
- "엄밀히 말하면"
- 그렇다면
- I said I didn't technically.
- Okay.
우리 할머니 반지 "우연히" 주워서..
Let's put aside the fact
that you "accidentally"..
레이첼한테 "우연히" 청혼한 거라구?
picked up my grandmother's ring and
you "accidentally" proposed to Rachel.
잠깐, 하나만 물어보자
Can I just stop you there
for a second?
사람들이 말하다가 이러는거
When people do this:
난 무슨 뜻인지 모르겠더라
I don't really know what that means.
하던 얘기 계속해
You were saying?
레이첼한테 차마 사실대로
말 못한건 이해가 가
And I could even understand
that you couldn't tell Rachel.
나한텐 말했어야지!
하루종일 보면서도 말 안했잖아!
But why couldn't you tell me?
You had all day to, and you didn't.
그래, 내가 잘못했어
"미안해"
I know. I should've.
"I'm sorry."
그렇게 쓰는게 아냐
Not using it right, Joe.
'미안해'
"I'm sorry."
- 가야겠다
- 안돼
- I'm gonna go.
- No, come on.
- 이 문제 해결해야지
- 봉지 이리 내
- Ross, we have to get past this.
- Give me the bag.
내가 어떡하면 좋겠니?
미안하다고 했잖아
No, I don't know what else to do.
I said I'm sorry, now..
나한테 소리를 지르던
욕을 하던 때리던 해!
Now you should scream at me
or curse me or hit me.
내가 왜 널 때리냐
- I'm not gonna hit you.
- You'll feel better. I'll feel better.
기분 풀어질거야!
나도 덜 미안할거구!
너도 때리고 싶잖아
얼굴에 다 써있어
You know you want to,
I can see it in your eyes.
- 그렇지 않아
- 살짝 써있어
- I don't.
- A little bit.
- 그렇지 않아
- 살짝 써있어
- No.
- Little bit.
- 아냐
- 그래 그렇게
- No.
- A little bit more.
- 이리줘, 내놔
- 어서 쳐, 날 쳐!
- Give me the bag. Give me the bag.
- No, hit me. Hit me.
- 어서 달라니까
- 날 치라니까!
- Give me the bag. I'm not kidding.
- Hit me.
- 장난 아냐!
- 쳐! 치란 말야! 어서!
- No.
- Hit me. Hit me. Hit me!
- 피하면 어떡해!
- 미안해! 반사적인 거였어!
- You ducked!
- I'm sorry! It was a reflex!
- 아! 엄청 아프단 말야!
- 어쩔수 없었어!
- Oh, my God! This really hurts!
- I couldn't help it.
주먹이 날아오면
피하게 돼있잖아! 봐!
When a fist comes at your face,
you duck. Look.
너 진짜 왜이래!
What is the matter with you?
피해야지! 왜 안피해?
You were supposed to duck!
Why didn't you?
그얘긴 병원가면서
하는게 어때?
Let's talk on the way to the hospital.
그래, 병원가서 네 반사신경도
좀 검사해보자
Good. Yeah, maybe while we're there,
they can check your reflexes.
"미안"
- 한번 더 먹여봐
- 벌써 먹였어!
- Try feeding her again.
- I already fed her.
알아!
그러니까 '더'라고 했잖아!
I know. That's why I said, "Again!"
우리끼리 싸우지 말자
You guys,
we can't turn on each other, okay?
아기가 원하는게 그거야
That's just what she wants.
- 나 왔어
- 어서와
- Hi.
- Hey.
내가 애정의 조건 보도록
놔두지 말라고 했잖아
I told you you shouldn't have
let her watch Terms of Endearment.
- 밖에서 잠깐 얘기좀 할래?
- 여기서 해
- Can I talk to you outside?
- Just stay here.
난 들어가서 기저귀좀 보고올께
피비, 같이 갈래?
I'm gonna check her diaper.
Phoebe, you want to come?
난 이쪽편 할래
I'm kind of part of this.
이건 부부끼리
할 얘기야, 피비
Actually, it's a husband-and-wife
kind of thing.
챈들러랑 결혼할걸 그랬어!
I knew I should've married Chandler.
- 무슨 일이야?
- 좋아
- Okay, what's up?
- Okay.
파리에서 1년정도 살면
재밌겠다고 했던거 기억나?
You know we said it would be fun
to move to Paris for a year?
자긴 프랑스요리 배우고
난 글쓰고..
And you could study French cooking,
and I could write..
세느강변도 산책하고
보르도에서 와인도 마시고
and we could picnic along the Seine,
and go wine-tasting in Bordeaux.
- 좋지
- 그래
- Yeah.
- Okay.
사람들이 '털사'를..
You know how people say
that Tulsa..
'오클라호마의 파리'라고
하는거 알아?
is the Paris of Oklahoma?
뭐? 누가 그래?
What? Who says that?
파리에 한번도 안가본 사람들?
People who have never been
to Paris?
- 무슨 일이야?
- 털사로 이사가야해
- Well, what's going on?
- We're moving to Tulsa.
- 뭐라구?
- 자 들어봐
- Excuse me?
- Okay.
매켄나라고 우리
상사가 있는데
Ms. McKenna,
she kind of works above my boss.
- 당신이 만난적이 있어
- 상관 안해, 털사얘길 해보라구
- I think you actually met her.
- Don't care. Get back to Tulsa.
나더러 털사에 있는
지점을 맡으래
She asked me to move to Tulsa
and be president of our office there.
그런데 졸다가 얼떨결에
그렇게 한다고 해버렸어
And I was sleeping
and apparently said yes.
- 털사? 오클라호마?
- '일찍 정착한 주!'
- Tulsa, Oklahoma?
- The Sooner State.
무슨 뜻인지는 모르지만
Whatever that is.
난 뮤지컬 오클라호마도
볼 생각 없어!
Chandler, I don't even want to see
the musical Oklahoma.
정말? '아름다운 아침',
'장식달린 4륜마차'도 싫어?
"Oh, What a Beautiful Morning,"
"Surrey With the Fringe on Top"?
지금 이사가자는 거야?
아님 자기가 게이라는 거야?
Are you trying to tell me we're moving
to Oklahoma or that you're gay?
이번건 거부할수 없는거 같아
I don't think I can get out of this.
- 세상에 이럴수가
- 모르는 일이야..
- Oh, my God!
- But you don't know..
파리 같을수도 있어
요리 강습도 배울수 있고
it could be like Paris.
You can still take a cooking class..
오럴 로버츠 대학에서 말야
at Oral Roberts University.
그 문제는 둘째치고
그러면 월급은 많이 준대?
All right, not that this matters, but did
they at least offer you a huge raise?
아니, 대신 포드 자동차 빌려준대
No. But they are going to lease us
a Ford Focus.
- 해결하고 올께
- 고마워
- I'll get out of it.
- Thank you.
엠마 왜 저래?
- What is wrong with Emma?
- She misunderstood.
자기가 털사로 이사가는 줄
착각했나봐!
She thought she was moving to Tulsa.
저어..
시간 있으세요?
Ma'am, do you have a minute?
안좋은 소식입니다
저 털사로 못갈것 같아요
I kind of have some bad news.
I don't think I can move to Tulsa.
- 뭐라구요?
- 그게 참 웃기는 얘기예요
- What?
- It's a funny story, actually.
실은 아침 회의때
제가 졸았거든요
I kind of fell asleep
in the meeting this morning.
털사로 가겠다고 한건
모르고 대답한 거예요
So when I said I'd move to Tulsa,
I didn't really know what I was saying.
졸았다구요?
You fell asleep?
회의걱정 하느라
밤을 꼴딱 샜거든요!
But only because I was up all night
worried about this meeting.
정말 웃기죠?
Isn't that funny?
아이러니예요
재미없으세요?
Irony. Not a fan? All right.
그런데 문제가 생겼어요
See, here's the thing.
집사람한테 얘기했더니
자긴 못간대요
I went home and told my wife
about Tulsa, and she won't go.
전 털사 좋아합니다
천국이 따로 없죠
See me, I love Tulsa. Tulsa is heaven.
Tulsa is ltaly.
제발 거기 보내지 마세요!
Please don't make me go there.
- 챈들러, 나는..
- 화나신거 압니다
- Chandler, I..
- I know that you're upset..
하지만 전 정말
여기에 머물기를 바래요
but I just.. I would really
rather just stay here.
아니 이 사무실을 말하는게 아니고요
Not here in your office..
여기 회사 말입니다
here at the company..
근데 갑자기 제가 이곳에서
환영을 못받는거 같네요
where I'm rapidly feeling unwelcome.
아뇨, 캐롤
이름 불러도 될까요?
No, look, Carol.
Can I call you Carol?
참, 캐롤이 아니라
일레인이죠?
Why would I
when your name is Elaine?
아드님 사진인가봐요?
아주 건장한데요?
What a great picture of your son.
Strapping.
따님 사진이군요?
That's a picture of your daughter,
isn't it?
예쁘네요! 전 턱이 각진
여자를 좋아하죠!
Well, she's lovely.
I like a girl with a strong jaw.
털사에 가서 연락드릴께요
I'll call you from Tulsa.
어때?
Hey. So how is it?
- 엄지가 부러졌대
- 엄지?
- I broke my thumb.
- Your thumb?
희한하네
제대로 치긴 쳤니?
That's weird.
Are you sure you're punching right?
주먹좀 쥐어봐
Make a fist.
나중에
Maybe later.
로스, 정말 미안하다
Ross, I feel terrible.
먼저가
난 이거 써서 내야해
You know what, you can go.
I just have to fill out some forms.
내가 도와줄까?
You want me to help you with that?
손가락이 이상하게 생겨서
고생하는것 같냐?
Why, does it look like I'm having
trouble with my misshapen claw?
이름?
Name?
로스라는건 알아
그게 뭐 줄인 이름이냐구
No, I know Ross.
But what's it short for?
로셀?
You know, like Rossell.
로스트로퍼?
Or Rosstrophor.
그냥 로스야!
Just Ross.
멋진 이름이네
It's pretty.
- 생일?
- 내 생일 알잖아
- Okay, date of birth?
- You know my birthday.
알지
Sure.
5.. 9월?
May.. tember?
- 10월 18일
- 직업? 공룡
- October 18.
- Occupation? Dinosaurs.
난 고생물학자..
그냥 공룡이라고 써라
Actually, I'm a paleon..
Dinosaurs is fine.
그림은 그리지 말고!
The drawing is not.
좋아, 비상시 연락처는?
All right, who do you want
as your emergency contact?
- 레이첼
- 좋아, 관계?
- Rachel, I guess.
- Okay. Relationship?
쓰자면 책 한권 나오지
Boy, this could take a while.
- 그냥 룸메이트라고 써
- 이봐
- Just put roommate.
- Come on.
그냥 룸메이트는 아니지
너희들 다시 합칠 거잖아?
You guys are more than that.
You're gonna get together, right?
아닐것 같은데?
I don't think that we are.
다시 시작하기로 한거 아냐?
But you two are supposed
to be together.
그렇게 생각했는데 레이첼이
너랑 결혼한다고 했잖아
Well, I thought so too.
But then she said she'd marry you.
그건 아무 의미없는거야
Come on, Ross,
that didn't mean anything.
애를 혼자키워야 한다는
생각에 겁이 났던 거라구
She'd just had the baby. She was
freaked out about doing it alone.
- 내가 아니라 누구였데도 승락했을거야
- 레이첼도 그렇게 말하더라
- She would have said yes to anybody.
- Yeah, that's what she said.
- 그런데?
- 난 그런 '아무나'가 되고 싶지않아
- So?
- So I don't want to be just anybody.
- 와
- 어..
- Wow.
- You know what?
이편이 더 나은것 같아
It's better this way anyway.
옛날로 다시 돌아가서
뭘 어쩌자는 거였는지..
I don't know what I was thinking,
going down that road again with us.
이편이 더 쉽지 않을까?
아기가 있는 친구사이
It's just much easier if we're
just friends who have a kid.
- 진심이야?
- 그래
- Really?
- Yeah.
- 그래도 괜찮겠어?
- 항상 그러자고 했었는걸
- And you're okay with that?
- Yes. That's what we always planned.
계획이 있으면 거기에
충실해야지
And if you have a plan,
you should stick to it.
계획이란게 그래서
있는거 아냐?
That's why they call them plans.
Hello?
난 괜찮아
I'm fine.
잘 모르겠지만 레이첼한테
Hey, for what it's worth..
넌 결코 "아무나"가 아냐
with Rachel, I don't think
you'll ever be just "anybody."
그래, 그렇게 쓰는거야!
Hey, there you go.
"고마워"
"Thanks."
도대체 몇시간째
우는거야?
Oh, my God.
How long has she been crying?
열흘쯤 됐을걸?
About a week and a half.
너희들끼리 잘 할수있지?
그럼 나 가볼께
Well, it looks like you guys got it
under control, so I'm just gonna go.
안돼? 정말? 불행은
나눠야 한다는 거지?
No? Really?
Misery really does love company?
좋아!
All right.
- 레이첼, 다른 쪽으로 안아봐
- 나 할수 있는건 다했어
- Try holding her a different way.
- Look, I'm doing the best I can.
- 누구 다른 사람이 좀 해봐
- 좋아, 내가 해볼께
- Anyone else is welcome to try.
- All right, I'll try. Fine.
- 좋아
- 그래
- Yes. Okay. Okay.
- Here you go.
- 자, 여기
- 오, 저런
Hey. Oh, gosh.
얜 구제불능이야!
Nothing works with this child!
나 어떡해? 자기 애 하나도
달래지 못하다니!
God, what am I gonna do, you guys?
I can't even comfort my own baby.
- 난 형편없는 엄마야!
- 처음이라 그래
- I'm the worst mother ever.
- No, you're just new at this.
점점 나아질거야
회사 처음 갔을때 생각해봐
You'll get better. Think about
your first day at work.
어려웠지만 잘 헤쳐갔잖아
That couldn't have been easy,
but you figured that out.
얘 앞에선 옷 야하게
입는게 도움이 안되잖아!
Yeah, I don't think dressing
provocatively is going to help me here!
- 얘좀 안아줄래?
- 내가 안을께
- God, just please take her.
- Okay, I'll take her. Come on.
화장실좀 가야겠다
Oh, boy,
I have to go to the bathroom.
난 베개에 얼굴묻고
비명 질러야겠어
I have to go scream into a pillow.
둥가 둥가 둥가 까꿍!
Bouncy. Bouncy baby. Bouncy baby.
예쁜 아기 착한 아기
Oh, baby, baby. Oh, baby, baby.
둥가 둥가
Oh, baby, baby, baby.
나 귀 먹은거야?
Have I gone deaf?
효과가 있어!
둥가 둥가 우리 아기
It worked. Oh, baby, baby, baby.
Oh, baby, baby, baby.
숨은 실력자가 여기있었네!
You must be a fireball in bed!
이것봐! 잠들었어!
내가 엠마를 재웠어!
I can't believe it. She's asleep.
I got her to go to sleep.
나한테 마법의 힘이 있나봐!
I have actual magical powers.
자동차 소리, 새소리가 들려
I can hear traffic and birds.
머릿속에서 들리던 목소리도
다시 들리구!
I can hear the voices in my head again.
농담이야
I'm kidding.
세상에!
울음을 멈췄네!
Oh, my God!
You got her to stop crying!
내가 달랬어!
슈퍼 고모 모니카라구!
Yes, I did. I'm Monica, super aunt.
- 널 공식 '우는 애 해결사'로 인정할께
- 그래
- You are the official baby-crier stopper.
- Yes, I am.
- 우리 집에서 나가지마
- 뭐라구?
- You're never leaving the apartment.
- Say what?
네 새로운 임무야
밤이고 낮이고 애 울면 네가 맡아
That's your new job, day or night.
She starts crying, I need you here.
- 오, 안돼
- 다행이다, 난 전혀 필요없는 거지?
- No, no, no.
- Thankfully, you don't need me at all.
얘, 슈퍼고모?
나중에 보자
So okay. Hey, super aunt?
See you later.
레이첼?
넌 반년 후에나 보자
Rachel?
Let's give it six to eight months.
자, 난 잠좀 자야겠어
Okay, so listen,
I'm gonna go lay down.
뭐?
What?
아기가 잘때
엄마도 자야한댔어
The book says whenever
she's sleeping, I should be sleeping.
그러니까..
So..
수고좀 해줘
Thank you.
안녕
Hey.
- 쉿! 방금 잠들었어!
- 그럼 소리 지르면 안되겠네?
- We just got her to go to sleep.
- So there can't be any yelling?
맞아
No.
- 아무래도 털사로 이사가야겠어
- 뭐야?
- We're moving to Tulsa.
- What?
무슨 말인지 안들려!
I can't.. I can't hear.
- 나 왔어
- 어디 갔었어?
- Hey.
- Hey. Where have you been?
- 어떻게 된거야?
- 조이랑 일이 좀 있었어
- What happened to you?
- I had a little thing with Joey.
내가 이정도면
조이는 어떻겠어?
If you think this is bad,
you should see him.
이러면 안돼
No, Ross, this is not good.
우리 얘기좀 해
앉아봐
We have to talk about this Joey thing.
Please sit.
조이 일 이제 그만 풀어
All right, you have got to get over
this Joey thing.
나 조이랑 결혼할 생각
조금도 없었어
Okay? I never really wanted
to marry Joey, okay?
알았어
Okay.
내가 정말 원하는게
뭔지 알아?
You know what I really, really want?
뭔데?
What, Rach?
자고 싶어!
I wanna sleep.
먹고 싶고!
샤워도 하고 싶어!
I wanna eat.
I wanna take a shower.
아기 꺠기전에 말야
깨면 또 다시 전쟁이야
I mean, before she wakes up,
and we gotta do this all over again.
- 그래
- 왜냐하면 말야
- Right.
- I mean, because I got news for you.
우리 엠마, 까다로워
Emma: not easy.
그래서 내가 여기 있잖아
Well, that's what I'm here for.
- 내가 가볼까?
- 아냐, 괜찮아
- You want me to get that?
- No, that's really okay.
- 모니카?
- 알았어! 알았다구!
- Monica?
- Got it, got it, got it, got it.
내가 곰곰이 생각해봤는데
정말 내 잘못 아냐
I've been thinking about this.
And I gotta tell you, it's not my fault.
- 그건 본능이었다고
- 무슨 얘기야?
- It's a natural instinct.
- What are you talking about?
이리와봐
내가 이러면 넌 어떡할래?
Okay, what would you do if I did this?